Resumé/CV





**Email** contact@nicholaspagonis.com

### Introduction

Greetings! My name is Nicholas Pagonis. I currently attend John Septimus Roe Anglican Community School and enjoy improving my clinical expertise in First Aid during my spare time as well as heavily participating in the Scouting movement. After graduating from school, I intend to become a Paramedic by studying at Curtin University and building my tactical knowledge with the Department of Fire and Emergency Services. From the age of 13, I obtained my Certificate of Resuscitation and followed the path of rescue by completing my Bronze Medallion with Royal Life Saving WA. I bring professionalism and quick response to the workplace and regularly act to gain these skills. To add, I am what's often referred to as a natural leader, meaning take charge of most situations unless instructed not to.

### Education

John Septimus Roe Anglican Community School 2007 - Present

## **Skills**

My skill range is very broad in the sense that I challenge myself in different areas consistently. I have developed various types of skills from Scouts which empower me in an outdoor domain, for example; rock climbing, abseiling, hiking, etc. The Scouting environment has also brought me very close to members of the State Emergency Service and has taught me different types of search and rescue techniques. On the opposite side of the spectrum, I am also very technologically inclined as you can see from my unique email address. Programs like Microsoft Word and Excel come very naturally to me in addition to other miscellaneous applications like Adobe Photoshop, which I am still a novice at. I am not only well educated in desktop programs but am also somewhat proficient in different code languages such as PHP, HTML and Javascript.

# Experience



## **Swimming Instructor**

Department of Education, Western Australia Dec 2020 - Present

The Department of Education runs seasonal swimming series across various location within Western Australia. A swimming instructor at the Department of Education offers; vital swimming and water safety skills, lessons for beginner, intermediate and advanced swimmers, a variety of programs ranging from five to ten days, opportunities to progress through stages 1-16 and obtain Bronze Medallion, lessons at over 180 pool and beach locations throughout Western Australia and friendly, qualified swimming staff.



### Swimming Instructor

City of Swan, Swan Active Beechboro Jan 2021 - Present

During the 2019-2020 summer holidays I completed the two day AUSTswim course and proceeded to begin the required practical hours. On the 7th of March I took the practical swimming assessment and passed with flying colours meaning I am now a qualified swimming instructor. From the end of January to the present day I have completed a multitude of hours in practical teaching and completed lesson plans to accompany my practical skills.

Resumé/CV







# Swimming Instructor (Prac)

City of Stirling, Terry Tyzack Aquatic Centre Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

During the 2019-2020 summer holidays I completed the two day AUSTswim course and proceeded to begin the required practical hours. On the 7th of March I took the practical swimming assessment and passed with flying colours meaning I am now a qualified swimming instructor. From the end of January to the present day I have completed a multitude of hours in practical teaching and completed lesson plans to accompany my practical skills.



### Employee/Helper

The Entertainment Bank May 2018 - Present

The Entertainment Bank provides entertainment facilities for all ages but specifically for children. Activities like operating an Easter bunny suit or walk Santa around a shopping complex. Maintaining the safety of clients and patrons was of paramount importance whilst also maintaining client satisfaction for future events.

# **Volunteer Experience**



#### **State Emergency Service**

Jan 2020 - Present

#### Probationary Member

Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

As a probationary member in the SES, my role was to learn all the basic rescue skills and assist the unit management in performing basic tasks whilst completing the induction education program.

#### Rescue Team Member

Aug 2020 - Present

A Rescue Team Member attends training sessions, emergency callouts and provides vital support to the community in times of need. Upon activation, a Rescue Team Member can be assembled into a Rescue Team, lead by a qualified Team Leader, to take part in land searches, flood boat rescue, storm damage repairs, ground support in large incident and mass casualty rescues at a moments notice.



#### Cadet First Aider

St John WA Jan 2020 - Present

St John WA provides leading event medical services from its Event Health Services (EHS) department. Within EHS, volunteers and paid staff treat patients and aid emergency incidents with their clinical expertise. The role of a Cadet First Aider is to provide advanced first aid to patrons if the need arises.

Resumé/CV







# Scouts WA May 2011 - Present

#### Youth Leader

Jan 2020 - Present

In Scouts there are 5 sections which are broken up into age increments. I am a youth leader in the Scout section (10-14 y.o) which means I have the same privileges as an adult leader and also the same responsibilities. What makes me a leader in Scouts is the ability to teach the youth new and useful skills that can bee used in their day to day life.

#### **Unit Leader**

Jan 2020 - Present

Within my home Scout group, I ran a Venturer Unit which is comprised of youth aged 14-18 for the duration of the year. Throughout the year I developed strong leadership and communication skills amongst my team and gained a better insight on the way my unit operates.

#### You+Lead Participant

Sep 2019

In September, Scouts WA paid for my flight to Queensland to attend a national leadership course with participants all over the country. It was quite easily the best 5 days of my life. At the course we learnt leadership skills, relationship strategies and much more. For more details, contact the Assistant National Commissioner Youth Program, Johnathan Morey johnathan.morey@scouts.com.au

#### You+Lead Course Leader

May 2020

On the other end of the You+Leader spectrum, I, along with four other Scouts who also went to Queensland, ran the first section of the You+Lead course in WA. We delivered important leadership skills to 50 other Scouts by expressing the importance of the different elements involving leadership. These skills and techniques can be used in the Scouts' everyday life and the workplace.

Resumé/CV





# **Certifications & Qualifications**

Name	Code	Accredited	Status
Provide First Aid	HLTAID003	Yes	Completed
Provide Basic Life Support	HLTAID002	Yes	Completed
Provide Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation	HLTAID001	Yes	Completed
Instruct Swimming Strokes	SISCAQU010	Yes	Completed
Instruct Water Safety and Survival Skills	SISAQU009	Yes	Completed
Instruct Water Familiarisation, Buoyancy and Mobility Skills	SISCAQU008	Yes	Completed
Perform Basic Water Rescues	SISCAQU002	Yes	Completed
Certificate II in Business	BSB31115	Yes	Completed
Certificate II in Active Volunteering	CHC24015	Yes	Completed
Working With Children's Check	CUASS00054	Yes	Completed
Hand Hygiene and Infection Prevention and Control	-	No	Completed
Infection Control Training COVID-19	-	No	Completed
National Police Clearance	-	Yes	Completed
Cadet First Aider	-	No	Completed
Bronze Medallion	-	No	Completed
Certificate of Resuscitation	-	No	Completed